Geetanjali Asiwal

Ph: (M): +91- 9667988187 Email: gitu.asiwal@gmail.com

## SEO Expert with 8 years of experience

#### **Profile:**

Hi, I am Geetanjali Asiwal, with 7+ years of experience in executing integrated search engine optimization campaigns for agencies and clients, the spectrum of online marketing elements ranging from search engine marketing, social media optimization to web analytics. I possess strong multi-tasking skills, with the ability to simultaneously manage several projects and schedules.

## Key skills & knowledge

- Search Engine Optimization
- Google Analytics (Insights & Report)
- Content Marketing & Outreach
- Pre-sales Support, Business Pitching for SEO.
- Web marketing & competitive intelligence.

## **Proficiency in tools**

- Certifications: Google Ads
- Paid Marketing: Google Ads, Facebook Ads
- SEO Tools: Ahref, SEMrush, MOZ, GSC, Screaming Frog
- Web Analytics: Google Analytics, Google Data Studio, UTM building, Channel setting in GA, GA4 Reporting
- Software: WordPress, Excel, power point etc
- Website Platform: WordPress, Shopify (Self SEO implementation)

# **Career Highlights**

- 40+ successfully Projects in SEO including Travel, sports, real estate, electrical products, hospitality, FMCG, auto, ecommerce, fashion, Education, News & health.
- Interest areas in digital marketing analysis, audit, strategies, and research.

### **Work Experience**

# **The Lotus Biotech**

September 16, 2024 to till now

# **SEO Specialist**

- Develop and execute successful SEO strategies
- Manage team of SEO Specialists
- Conduct keyword research to guide content teams
- Review technical SEO issues and recommend fixes
- Optimize website content, landing pages
- Direct off-page optimization projects
- Collect data and report on traffic, rankings and other SEO aspects
- WordPress Handling & product upload as well

#### **SEO Analyst**

- Spearheaded the entire SEO business operation from SEO account management to new pitches and planning to execution of SEO services for US clients & increased annual 2023-24 SEO revenue by 34% vs 2022-23.
- Work in conjunction with Marketing & Business Leads, and vendor partners, to perform gap analysis & SEO approach and ensure adherence to strict timelines, compliances & brand standards.
- Successfully strategized & executed organic search & content campaigns for premium clients such as Travolook.in, Jaybirdsport, Deguns, Luxury hotels group & increased organic traffic and revenue.

# Affiliation Technology (Janakpuri)

April 01, 2019 to May 25, 2023

#### **Senior SEO Executive**

- Managing three people for off-page execution, SMO and paid campaigns.
- Responsible for managing whole team for seo and content writing.
- Connecting with clients as well if need any changes.
- Complete On-page optimization according to Search Engine guidelines.
- Responsible for managing all off-page activities.
- Acquire backlinks from various sources including article submission, comments on third party websites, blog submission, social bookmarking & image submissions.

# Webpulse Solution Pvt. Ltd. (Kirti Nagar)

Jan 22, 2018 to Jan 15, 2019

## **Senior SEO Executive**

- Creating quality backlinks
- Learning Google Analytics and Search Console.
- Responsible for managing & optimization of 8 Ecommerce, Auto, Travel and Food websites.
- Weekly coordination with brand team to discuss SEO progress.
- Competitor research to identify new SEO ideas.

# **Active India Digital Products (Shadipur)**

**October 2016 to Jan 2018** 

#### **SEO Executive**

- Managing three people for off-page execution, SMO and paid campaigns.
- I was responsible for managing whole team for seo and content writing.
- Connecting with clients as well if need any changes.

# Vodafone (Peeragarhi)

Feb 2015 to Jan 2016

#### **Backend**

• Handling E-mails and query resolutions.

## Qualification

- MCA from Punjab Technical University
- BCA from Bharati Vidyapeeth University, Delhi
- Diploma in Computer Science from GPW, Faridabad

# **Projects highlights**

- Travolook (Travel)
- Gomechanic (Vehicle Repair & Maintenance)
- ITC Ltd (Hospitality)
- ITC Masterchef (Food)
- Jaquar Lighting (e-commerce)
- CenturyProwud ()
- Maharashtra Times(News)
- Galaxy Toyota (e-commerce)
- GenesLecoanetHemant (e-commerce)
- Jaybirdsport (e-commerce)
- Royal Enfield (Corporate & e-commerce website)
- Amar Ujala (Hindi Newspaper)
- Avis Car Rental (Travel)
- The Montcalm Hotels (A chain of 5-star hotels in London)
- Sai Furniture Art
- Barber Syndicate
- Adotrip India
- Veemaan and many more

### **Personal Details**

Current Location: R-101B 2<sup>nd</sup> Floor, Khirki Extension, Malviya Nagar, New Delhi – 110017

Date of Birth: Nov 16, 1990

Nationality: Indian
Marital Status: Married
Language: English & Hindi

Date:	GEETANJALI ASIWAL
Place:	